Terrence Ricardo John

Address

11 Pommecythere Court, Santa Rosa Heights, Arima,

Trinidad & Tobago

Email (Work) **Email (Personal)** tj6613@ttec.co.tt terrence1019@gmail.com Mobile 1-868-363-2915 Home 1-868-230-3374

Profile

Career Overview

An adaptable and persevering developer, with over a decade's worth of IT experience, determinedly seeking a challenging Software Developer position in the Software Services Section of the Information Systems Department. Highly interested in working in an environment where possessing strong skills in communication, critical thinking, problem solving, documentation, and organization are considered powerful assets contributive to its growth and productivity.

Proficient when working with teams and independently for analyzing difficult problems and developing simplified-yet-innovative solutions that consistently work. Equipped with a logical mindset enabling a strong capacity for in-depth learning and rapid application of new knowledge. Committed to maintaining the highest levels of professional and personal excellence gained from 17 years of discipline and experience, ensuring maximum performance and efficiency is dedicated to the Department and to the Commission as a whole.

Experience

Independent Software Development Work

Repository for Developer Profile and Coding Projects

Repository Link

GitHub

https://www.github.com/terrence1019

Replit

https://www.replit.com/@terrence1019

The Trinidad & Tobago Electricity Commission

Position

Timeline

rimeinie	1 0310011	Duties
2020 - Present	Computer Operator II, End User Support, Information Systems, Head Office	 Provide assistance to Software Services Staff in the resolution of technical issues Uphold the Information Systems Department Guidelines in terms of code of conduct, communication, and performance of duties Engage in walkthroughs with users (in person, by phone, or remotely) to assess their situation in order to get to the root of the problem Cautiously analyze and decipher the information provided by users on Trouble Report Forms

• Systematically troubleshoot and resolve faults in conformity with good IT practices

- Conduct follow-ups with users to ensure implemented solutions are effective
- Properly identify and document solutions for hardware and software issues encountered
- Provide detailed solutions and recommendations for problems to fellow team
- Provide users with thorough feedback on the problem, the solution, and recommendations to avoid future occurrences of the issue
- Configuration of hardware and software for newly assigned devices in accordance with the required standards of the Information Systems Department
- Set up new user accounts and profiles, and resolve user access issues or requests
- Carry out necessary repairs or replacements of damaged or exhausted parts
- Fill out relevant reports regarding work done on computer equipment
- Conduct quality and safety checks on incoming and outgoing computer equipment
- Efficiently prioritize and manage multiple reports simultaneously
- Provide timely and accurate feedback to both Tech Support team and users regarding status updates on cases being handled
- Establish and maintain good working relationships and rapport with Tech Support
- Configure and utilize Remote Access to networked resources through a variety of methods such as Radmin, Windows Virtual Desktop, and Team Viewer

Timeline **Position Duties** Computer Operator II, 2012 - Present • Uphold the Information Systems Department Guidelines in terms of code of conduct, communication, and performance of duties IS Operations, • Execute procedures required to validate and update customer payment transaction Information Systems, data to the Commission's financial databases **Head Office** • Process the data files related to customers' consumption readings in preparation for bi-monthly Customer Billing • Run the Charge Calculation and Bill Print business processes required for accurate Customer Billing • Successfully uphold the mandated printing schedule of Customer Bills, for a specified period, based on Customer Rating Class (Domestic/General, Industrial, Street Lighting, and Pole Rental Accounts) Schedule essential business processes to automatically execute during after-work Conduct periodic backups to safeguard critical and sensitive data of processes successfully run • Process, verify, and distribute remuneration and other financial reports required by the Payroll, Pensions, Human Resource, and Finance Departments • Initiate corrective actions in the event of a job error or job abortion Conduct maintenance and audit checks for equipment and stock supplies required for carrying out daily duties Clerk III, 2007 - 2012 • Assigned to the Field Office of the Eastern Distribution Area and tasked with the responsibility of securing and managing all field equipment designated as either Field Office, high priority, heavy duty, or hazardous Operations, • Performed thorough audits of all inventory on a weekly basis Maintenance, and • Developed effective logging forms for monitoring inventory usage, in conjunction with pre-existing stock management measures Construction, • Accurately recorded the acquisition and distribution of inventory on a daily basis in Distribution East preparation for weekly and monthly assessment reports • Generated Purchase Orders and Material Stock Requisitions for replenishing critical supplies using the PeopleSoft Application Suite • Conducted careful testing and quality control checks of all supplies ordered or issued, minimizing faulty equipment hazards • Distributed essential tools, equipment, and safety gear required by linesmen and other types of field workers to perform their daily duties safely and effectively Managed the proper disposal of items that were damaged or exhausted from Supervised access to keys of area's vehicle fleet, and ensured proper insurance & registration documents were on-board at all times Partook in the exercise that assisted the Software Services Team in producing the in-house Vehicle Tracking System • Logged precise records of daily activity of vehicles using the Vehicle Tracking System • Recorded all daily maintenance and repair works carried out on vehicles by mechanics, in addition to stock supplies used in the process • Offered full cooperation to Internal Auditors performing their Annual Audits by providing all relevant stock records and information • Upheld an impressive Audit record for the position appointed to Messenger, 2005 - 2007 • Maintained accurate and detailed delivery logs of daily duties Delivered internal and external mail recognized as highly confidential and high Registry, priority in a safe, secure, and speedy manner Administration, • Carefully transferred sensitive bank documents and cheques to and from bank **Head Office** institutions, and critical legal documents to and from legal firms

Skills

Programming Languages

- C#
- JavaScript

- LINQ
- **■** C++

Web Development

■ HTMI

CSS

Databases

MySQL

■ Oracle

Development Frameworks & Stacks

Microsoft .NET Framework

Microsoft Entity Framework

Development & Testing Tools

- Microsoft Visual Studio
- GitHub

- MySQL Workbench
- Replit

Technical Support

- Software Configuration
- PC Troubleshooting & Repairs
- Help Desk Support
- Documentation Write-Up (Manuals & Walkthroughs)
- Hardware Configuration
- Remote Login & Troubleshooting
- PC Auditing

Operating Systems

Microsoft Windows

Apple iOS

Google Android

Microsoft Office Suite

Microsoft Word

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Outlook

- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Access

Education

Online Training

Institute		
PluralSight	• C# Fundamentals • .NET Framework Fundamentals	 Entity Framework Fundamentals Software Engineering Fundamentals
Courses Provided by the Commission in Partnership with Training Institutes	 Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals Microsoft Azure Fundamentals 	Al • Microsoft Azure Core Fundamentals

The University of the West Indies

Graduation Year	Merit Awarded	Key Courses Covered in Degree	
2018	BSc Information Technology (with Honors)		
		• Enterprise • Software • Information • Business Information Systems • Development • Business Information Systems	Engineering System Information

References

Referential Information for Personnel of The Trinidad and Tobago Electricity Commission

Larry Pinheiro,	Rudra Sankarsingh,	Eric Headley,
Systems Analyst III,	Systems Administrator I,	Senior Analyst,
Information Systems,	Information Systems,	Information Systems,
1-868-623-2611 (2631),	1-868-623-2611 (2626),	1-868-623-2611 (2620),
lpinheiro@ttec.co.tt	rsankarsingh@ttec.co.tt	eheadley@ttec.co.tt
Charlene John,	Utam Seepersad,	Kevin Castle,
Information Systems Manager,	Computer Operator I,	Network Administrator I,
Information Systems,	Information Systems,	Information Systems,
1-868-623-2611 (2600),	1-868-623-2611 (2641),	1-868-623-2611 (2650),
cjohn@ttec.co.tt	us6407@ttec.co.tt	kcastle@ttec.co.tt
Dominic Gay,	Devecar Basdeo,	Kwame Tuckett,
IT Support Supervisor,	Project Manager,	Field Controller,
Information Systems,	Enterprise Risk Management,	Field Office - Public Lighting,
1-868-623-2611 (2622),	1-868-623-2611 (2190),	1-868-623-2611 (4970),
dominic@ttec.co.tt	db5154@ttec.co.tt	kt6329@ttec.co.tt
Frank O'Connell,	Nigel Charles,	Lisa Cazoe,
Mechanical Assistant,	Consumer Liaison Officer,	Area Administrative Officer,
Field Office - Dist. East,	Regulatory & Compliance,	Admin - Dist. North,
1-868-623-2611 (7194),	1-868-623-2611 (2272),	1-868-623-2611 (1200),
fo1207@ttec.co.tt	nc3716@ttec.co.tt	lc3356@ttec.co.tt